A Guide to the Publications of the Virginia Economic Development Partnership, ca. 1954-2009
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Publications of the Virginia Economic Development Partnership, ca. 1954-2009
The Library of Virginia
50755
1.35 cubic feet
Virginia Economic Development Partnership
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred by the Virginia Economic Development Partnership, Research Division, on 02/07/2013.
Historical Information
In 1996 an act of the General Assembly split the Department of Economic Development into two newly created entities: the Virginia Economic Partnership (VEDP) and the Department of Business Assistance (DBA). VEDP is governed by a twenty-five member Board of Directors appointed by the Ggovernor & General Assembly from businessmen & women throughout Virginia. It's purpose is to foster the growth of Virginia's economy through business recruitment, expansion assistance, and trade development.
Scope and Content
The Publications of the Virginia Economic Development Partnership are housed in two boxes and are arranged alphabetically by title. This collection includes background reports, studies, memorandums, newsletters, and other publications kept by the Research Division of the Virginia Economic Development Partnership. The background reports were produced by the Division of Industrial Development on various industries such as electronics, motor vehicles, pharmaceuticals, plastics, etc., in the 1960s and 1970s. Also significant is a run of the Virginia Economic Review from 1958 to 1994, a newsletter published by the Virginia Division of Industrial Development, and later the Department of Economic Development. Lastly, there are sundry studies of cost analyses, foreign investment, and tax incentives for investing in Virginia.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Publications, ca. 1954-2009
Contents List
- Publications, ca. 1954-2009., Extent: 2 boxes.
  Arranged alphabetically by publication title.
  - Background Aircraft Report (SIC 3721), 1969 September. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Background Report: Construction & Related Machinery (SIC 353), 1972 January. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Background Report: Cosmetics & Toilet Preparations Study (SIC 2844), ca. 1970. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Background Report on Electric Motors & Generators (SIC 3621), ca. 1963. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Background Report on Electronic Computing Equipment, ca. 1972. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Background Report on the Electronics Industry, 1978 May. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Background Report on the Forest Products Industry, 1983 December. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Background Report on Industrialized Building, ca. 1971. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Background Report on the Instruments Industry, 1978 August. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Background Report: Machinery, Except Electrical (SIC 35), 1977 May. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Background Report on the Major Household Appliances Manufacturing Industry, ca. 1974. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Background Report on the Metalworking Machinery Industry, 1979 August. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Background Report on the Motor Vehicle Industry, 1979 August. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Background Report: Paints & Allied Products (SIC 2851), ca. 1963. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Background Report on Pharmaceutical Preparations (SIC 2834), ca. 1967 & 1975. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Background Report on the Plastic Products Industry, 1978 May. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Background Report on the Printing Industry, 1974 & 1977. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Background Report on the Printing & Publishing Industry (SIC 27), 1970. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Background Report on Scientific & Industrial Instruments, ca. 1969. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Background Report: Selected Metalworking Industries (SIC 34 & 35), 1974 October. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Background Report: Soap & Detergents (SIC 2841), ca. 1965. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Background Report on Wholesale Trade (For Warehouse & Distribution Cost Study), 1980 December. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Business Incentives, 2000-2001, 2005-2006, & 2008-2009. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Candy & Other Confectionary Products Industry, ca. 1964. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Comparative Analysis of Taxes of Manufacturers: Virginia and Selected States, 1971 December. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Comparative Cost of Manufacturing Scientific & Industrial Instruments in Virginia and Other States, 1978 August. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Comparative Costs of Opening a Metal Furniture Plant in Selected Localities in Virginia and Other States, 1964 November. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Comparative Costs of Operating a Refrigeration Machinery Plant in Selected Localities in Virginia and Other States, 1964 October. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Corporate & Regional Headquarters, 1972 March. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Cost Analysis of Operating a Glass Container Factory in Petersburg & Fredericksburg, Va., 1968 August. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Cost Comparison between Harrisonburg, Va., & Cleveland, OH, ca. 1964. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Establishing a New Standard of Leadership in an Evolving Technological Age, ca. 1983. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Foreign Export Study, 1996 March. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Foreign Investment in Virginia, 1982-2006. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Forest Products: Virginia's Shenandoah Region (Press Release), 1988. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Guide to Preparing an Orientation Program, n.d.. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Guide to Recruitment & Pre-Employment Assessment, 1992. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - High Technology: Electonics, A Background Report, 1981 November. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - High Technology in Virginia, 1984. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Internationally Owned Companies in Virginia, 2008-2009. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Joint Legislative Audit Review & Commission Recommendations (Memorandum), 1984. (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Manufacturing Earnings, 1982 January & April. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Medical Instruments Industry Study for the Commonwealth of Virginia, 1997 May. (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Motor Vehicle Parts: Cost Savings in Virginia, 1979 December. (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Nature of the Industry, ca. 1970. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Opportunity for Upgrading the Types of Industries that Can Consider Locating in Virginia's Rural Areas, ca. 1970. (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Preliminary Cost Analysis of Operating a Bicycle Plant in Petersburg, Va. & Little Falls, NY, 1968 January. (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Presentation to: The Southwest Economic Development Commission, 1985 August. (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Review of Economic Development in Virginia (Joint Legislative Audit & Review Commission Correspondence), 1991. (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Study of the Feasibility of Locating a Candy Manufacturing Plant in Virginia, 1964 April & September. (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Train the Trainer, n.d.. (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - U.I. Buyer's Digest, ca. 1954. (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Virginia Economic Review
    - 1958 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - 1959 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - 1960 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - 1961 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - 1962 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - 1963 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - 1964 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - 1965 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - 1967 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - 1968 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - 1970 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - 1971 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - 1972 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - 1975 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - 1976 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - 1977 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - 1978 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - 1980 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - 1981 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - 1982 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - 1983 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - 1984 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - 1985 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - 1986 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - 1987 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - 1988 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - 1989 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - 1990 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - 1991 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - 1993 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - 1994 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Virginia Firms with Foreign Affiliations, 1998 & 2000. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Guide to Local Taxes on Business, 2007-2008. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Virginia: An Opportunity for Greater Profitability in Manufacturing Plastic Products, 1978 May. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Virginia/Opportunity for Research & Development, ca. 1969. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Virginia's Industrial Opportunities in Plastics Products, 1962 January. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Virginia's Potential for a Coal Conversion Facility, ca. 1974. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Virginia's Role in Federal Research & Development, 1983. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Wage Survey of Selected Manufacturing Companies, 1983. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Wage Rates in Manufacturing: A Comparative Study, 1967. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Warehousing & Distribution Centers: Advantages of a Virginia Location, n.d.. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Water & Sewer Rates: Virginia Systems, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Wood as an Industrial Fuel, 1980. (Box 2, Folder 12)